Carlos Alejandro Zerga Morales

Senior Backend Developer

(+51) 993-762804 zerga.morales.carlos@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/carlos-zerga (GMT-5)Lima Peru

I'm a software engineer with +8 years of relevant experience developing web applications using Java, Python and REST services. Aiming to always maintain a code coverage upper to 90% in unit tests. Highly interested in Machine Learning and Al, I also already finished a Master's degree in Data Science to improve my skills. Currently working on NLP projects with documents in spanish.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Seeri/Java Backend Senior

Bogota Colombia — October, 2021 - Nowadays

Startup working on B2B technology in Colombia and Mexico, its main objective is to provide digital transformation to all specialized stores in Latin America through all stages: production, distribution and marketing between brands and local stores.

- Reduce operations time in 75% by doing integrations of payment, logistic and billing applications like: Mercadopago, Servientrega, Coordinadora, Siigo, EnvioClick
- Open a great opportunity for expansion by implementing a flow of integrations where each provider will choose which functionality to use such as: logistics, billing and payment gateways

<u>Tech-Stack:</u> Java, Spring Boot, Docker, Swagger, Mermaid, GCP, ElasticSearch, MySQL, AWS, Micronaut

Indigital/Java Backend Senior

Lima Peru — July, 2019 - February 2021

Company working on deep technology renovation in the Retail industry through Agora -a virtual bank, and delivery application- that currently has more than a million users and growing.

- Maintained microservices code coverage to 95% by implementing unit tests with JUnit
- Reduced software implementation efforts by 40% by providing Swagger and Sequence diagrams as technical documentation

Tech-Stack: Java, Spring Boot, Docker, Swagger, Mermaid, GCP, Azure Devops, ElasticSearch, MySQL

Yarkan Sac/Software Engineer

Lima Peru — February, 2018-June 2019

Company from the tourism industry with a huge presence in America and an increasing presence in Europe and Asia, building a B2B system for searching availability and booking tourist products, with a look-to-book rate of around 10% and over 2.5 million search results every 30 minutes. With clients around the world with a huge presence in America and increasing presence in Europe and Asia.

- Search engine costs reduction to 25% after meetings which give us a better understanding about what a search means for them
- Improved allowed searches per minute by 50% through the implementation of a new REST service deprecating a SOAP service

<u>Tech-Stack:</u> PHP, Zend Framework, Docker, Swagger, AWS, Jenkins, ElasticSearch, PostgreSQL

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, Python

Frameworks and Tools: SpringBoot, Micronaut, Docker, K8S, Swagger, Mermaid.js, Git, AWS, GCP

Languages: English, Advance; Spanish, Native; Portuguese, Basic

EDUCATION

Universidad Ricardo Palma-Lima, Peru

Master of Data Science, May 2020-2021, Supervised and Unsupervised Learning, Statistics modeling, Machine Learning, DeepLearning, BigData